Guide to the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Pittsburgh Section Records, 1946-1951, 1968-1991 AIS.1984.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Pittsburgh Section Records
1946-1951, 1968-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Pittsburgh Section
AIS.1984.09
5 Linear Feet (4 boxes)
The records of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Pittsburgh Section include by-laws, minutes of committees, reports of officers and committees, charts, manuals, activities files, and publications from 1946-1951 and 1968-1991.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the organization in 1984, 1985, 1990, and 1991.
Scope and Content Notes
The records of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Pittsburgh Section include by-laws, minutes of committees, reports of officers and committees, charts, manuals, activities files, and publications from 1946-1951 and 1968-1991.
History
The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers or IEEE is a non-profit professional association dedicated to advancing technological innovation related to electricity. It has more than 395,000 members in more than 160 countries, 45% outside the United States. The Pittsburgh Section, formed on October 3, 1902, is the third oldest section formed in the U.S. It was preceded by sections in Chicago (1883) and the Twin Cities (April 7, 1902).
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Pittsburgh Section Records, AIS.1984.09, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Electronics engineers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Electrical engineers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Publications; Associations; Minutes; Manuals (Instructional materials); Bylaws (Administrative records); Trade associations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Professional associations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Engineering -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Electrical engineering -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Societies, etc.; Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers. Pittsburgh Section
- History of Pittsburgh Section IEEE, Prepared by History Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
- Annual Report, 1946-1947
- Annual Report, 1949-1950
- Annual Report, 1950-1951
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1968-1969
- Roster of Section Executive Committee, 1968-1969
- Copies of Meeting Reports to National Headquarters, 1968-1969
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1968-1969
- Chairman's Annual Report, 1969-1970
- New By-laws, 1969-1970
- Secretary's Meeting Record, 1969-1970
- Financial Records, 1969-1970
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1969-1970
- Annual Reports of Standing Committees, 1969-1970
- Annual Reports of Subsection, 1969-1970
- Annual Reports of Group Chapters, 1969-1970
- Executive Committee Membership, 1970-1971
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970-1971
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1970-1971
- By-laws, 1970-1971
- Budget, 1970-1971
- Membership and Services Agreement, 1970-1971
- Treasurer's Report, 1970-1971
- Annual Reports of Group Chapters, 1970-1971
- Organization Roster, 1970-1971
- Meeting Reports, 1970-1971
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1972
- Handbook Fellow Grade Nominations, 1971-1972
- Awards An Invitation to Nominate, 1971-1972
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1971-1972
- Meeting Expense Report, 1971-1972
- Control System Society, 1971-1972
- Meeting Reports, 1971-1972
- Treasurer's Report, 1971-1972
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1972-1973
- Meeting Reports, 1972-1973
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1973-1975
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1973-1975
- Executive Committee Membership, 1975-1976
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1975-1976
- Project Pacesetter Task Force for Professional Organizations, 1975-1976
- Possible Additions to Operation Manual, 1975-1976
- Annual Report, 1975-1976
- By-laws, 1975-1976
- Organization Chart, 1975-1976
- Section Manual, 1975-1976
- Operations Manual, 1975-1976
- Annual Reports, 1976-1978 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1976-1978
- Executive Committee Meeting Attendance, 1976-1978
- Treasurer's Report, 1976-1978
- Registration of Engineers, 1976-1978
- Continuing Education Programs, 1976-1978
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1976-1978
- Executive Committee Membership, 1976-1978
- By-laws, 1976-1978
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980
- Treasurer's Report, 1978-1980
- Audit Reports, 1978-1980
- Executive Committee Membership, 1978-1980
- By-laws, 1978-1980
- Recognition Night Information, 1978-1980
- Annual Ballot Results, 1978-1980
- Investments, 1978-1980
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1978-1980
- Section Meetings, 1978-1980
- Chairman's Report, 1978-1980
- Annual Report, 1978-1980
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
- Executive Committee Membership, 1980-1982
- Treasurer's Report, 1980-1982
- Proposed Budget, 1980-1982
- Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1980-1982
- Secretary's Annual Reports, 1980-1982
- Annual Reports, 1980-1982
- Chapter Reports, 1980-1982
- Committee and Member at Large Reports, 1980-1982
- Examination for Region 2 Outstanding Section Award, 1980-1982
- Executive Committee Meeting Minutes, 1982-1983
- Audits, 1982-1983
- Nomination for Region 2 Outstanding Section Award, 1982-1983
- By-laws, 1982-1983
- Executive Committee Roster, 1982-1983
- Executive Committee Orientation Manual, 1982-1983
- Introduction to the Annual Report, 1982-1983
- Officer Reports, 1982-1983
- Committee Reports, 1982-1983
- Chapter Reports, 1982-1983
- Special Projects and Recognition, 1982-1983
- Student Activities and Continuing Education, 1982-1983
- Supporting and Reference Material, 1982-1983
- Annual Report, 1982-1983
- Section Bulletin (Vol. 6, #1-9; Vol. 8, #1-4, 8; Vol. 9, #7-9; Vol. 12, #5-6, 8-9; Vol. 13, #1-9; Vol. 14, #1-9; Vol. 15, #1-6, 8-9; Vol. 16, #1-2, 4, 7, 9; Vol. 17, #2-6, 9; Vol. 18, #1-4, 6-8; Vol. 19, #1-8; Vol. 20, #1-8; Vol. 21, #1-8; Vol. 26, #1-8; Vol. 27, #1-8; Vol. 28, #1-8; Vol. 29, #1-8; Vol. 30, #1-8), 1968-1982, 1986-1991
- Treasurer's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
- Tax Exempt Status of IEEE (Misc. Correspondence), 1982-1983
- Treasurer's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1983-1984
- Geographic Unit Financial Report to Hdqtrs (1984), 1983-1984
- Geographic Unit Financial Report to Hdqtrs (1984), 1983-1984
- Chairman's Annual Report, 1984-1985
- Secretary's Annual Report, 1984-1985
- IEEE Long Term Funds Correspondence, 1984-1985
- Orientational Manual (1984 Version), 1984-1985
- Annual Report, 1984-1985
- Secretary's File, 1985-1986
- Secretary's Annual Report, 1985-1986
- Geographic Unit Financial Report to Hdqtrs (1985), 1985-1986
- Treasurer's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1985-1986
- Secretary's Annual Report, 1986-1987
- Treasurer's Annual Report, 1986-1987
- Geographic Unit Financial Report to Hdqtrs (1986), 1986-1987
- Annual Audit Report to EXCOM, 1986-1987
- Upper Mon Subsection Annual Report, 1986-1987
- EXCOM Meeting Minutes, 1987-1988
- Geographic Unit Financial Report to Hdqtrs 1987., 1987-1988
- Treasurer's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1987-1988
- Annual Audit Report to EXCOM, 1987-1988
- IAS Annual Meeting Budget Request and Approval, 1987-1988
- EXCOM Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989
- Treasurer's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1988-1989
- Secretary's Annual Report to EXCOM, 1988-1989
- Chairman's Annual Report to Hdqtrs ((A detailed report that includes: EXCOM Meeting Minutes, Roster, Committee Reports, Group/Society Reports, Bulletins,Bylaws, etc.), 1989-1990
- Chairmen's Annual Report, 1990-1991